redislabs.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy | Redis Labs

_Last Updated: May 30, 2018_

**Redis Labs** (Redis Labs, Inc. and Redis Labs Ltd. and its affiliates) (“ **us** ”, “ **we** ” or “ **our** ”) provides this Privacy Policy (“ **Policy** ”) to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personally identifiable information we receive when you, as a user – 

  * visit www.redislabs.com (including any subdomains of this website or other websites owned by us or operated on our behalf) (the “ **Website** ”);
  * use any part of our services via the Site (the “ **Services** ”); 
  * download software (the “ **Software** ”) from the Site (collectively, the “ **Product** ”). 

This Policy applies only to information that you provide us through the Site or the Product (including any information provided as part of your subscription to the Software) or when you access or use any content appearing on the Site or made available through the Product, or that we collect on your behalf as part of the Product’s use. 

**A Summary of The Policy**

  1.     1. **Information That we Collect**  –If you register or purchase our Service, Software, or Products, we will need information such as your name, your company name, email address and password; your payment details to process payments, etc, and we automatically log IP addresses, browser information, etc. Read more. 
    2. **How we Use Personally Identifiable Information**  – We use Personally identifiable information to provide the Product, make it better and continue developing it, enforce terms, and protect us and the Service from misuse and law violations. Read more. 
    3. **The Personally** **Identifiable Information That You Upload**  – You can upload content with personally identifiable information. Please use caution and do not upload personally identifiable information of others without their appr#11 are information when we use service providers, for example, to process payments. We will transfer information when we change our corporate structure, and we will share information when required to do so by law enforcement or compliance requests. We also share information with our business affiliate entities. Read more.
    4. **Information Sharing and Disclosure** – We share information when we use service providers, for example, to process payments. We will transfer information when we change our corporate structure, and we will share information when required to do so by law enforcement or compliance requests. We also share information with our business affiliate entities. Read more.
    5. **Your California Privacy Rights** – If you are a California resident, you can request information about the third parties that we have disclosed your personally identifiable information to during the preceding year for their direct marketing purposes, and the types of categories of such personally identifiable information. Read more.
    6. **Your Choice**  – You may opt-out of our mailing lists and terminate your use of the Service. Our Service does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. Read more.
    7. **Accessing Your Personally** **Identifiable Information**  – At any time you can request access to your personally identifiable information. Read more.
    8. **Your EU Data Subject Rights –** If we process your personal data when you are in the EU, further terms apply to our processing in relation to your rights as a data subject under EU data protection laws. Read more.
    9. **Data Retention**  – We retain data to provide the service and for legitimate and lawful purposes. Read more.
    10. **Information Security**  – We implement systems, applications and procedures to secure your personally identifiable information, to minimize the risks of theft, damage, loss of information, or unauthorized access or use of information. Read more.
    11. **International Processing and Transfer** – We use cloud-based services to store and process data in the European Union and in the United States and will store them at additional sites, at our discretion. These service providers provide us adequate security and confidentiality commitments. Read more. 
    12. **Our Policy Toward Children –** If you are under the age of 16, you do not have permission to use the Website and the Product. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. Read More.
    13. **Dispute Resolution**  – Contact us at: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com) or write to us for any request and complaint. We will make good-faith efforts to resolve any existing or potential dispute with you. Read more.
    14. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**  – We will update our policy from time to time after giving proper notice. Read more.
    15. **Incorporation to the Terms of Use**  – This policy is an integral part of the Redis Labs Terms of Use or, if applicable, of any other Service subscription agreement entered into between you (or the entity that you are acting on its behalf) and us. Read More.
    16. **Contact Us** – Please contact our Privacy team at: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com) for further information.
    17. **Cookies**   **Addendum** – We use cookies to make it easier for you to log-in and to facilitate Service activities. Read more.

**The Redis Labs Privacy Policy**

#### **1\. Information That we Collect**

**Personally Identifiable Information**

As a condition to your use of the Product, we will ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that we can use to contact or identify you and administer your account. 

Personally identifiable information includes your name, company name, email address, telephone number, contact person details and financial information such as your credit/debit card details, your bank account details and your mailing address.

As a paying user of the Service, we will receive your payment transaction details from the payment service provider that processed your payment.

When you contact us, or when we contact you, we will receive and process any personally identifiable information that you provide us.

**Non-Identifiable Information**

When you access the Site or use the Product, we collect the following:

  * Information regarding your use of the Product and all information collected by us while providing you the Product;
  * Information that your browser sends whenever you visit the Site or use the Product(“ **Log Data** ”). This Log Data could include, for example, your computer’s Internet Protocol address, browser type, login information, the web page you were visiting before you came to the Site and information you search for on the Site
  * Information collected by the Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics about your visit, including the full website (uniform resource locators (URL)) clickstream (history) to, through and from our website (including date and time); 
  * Products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

When you use a widget or any other tool that may be offered by us, whether on the Site or on a third party website, including a website owned or operated by you, we may record data related to that activity, the deployment of the widget or tool and any other account related data.

Like many websites, we use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. 

We use “persistent cookies” to save your username and login credentials for future logins to the Site. We use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Product, to better understand how you interact with the Site and Product and to monitor web traffic routing on the Site and aggregate usage of the Product. 

You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the website you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionalities of the Product. 

Please see ADDENDUM A: Cookie Policy, which identifies our privacy policy with respect to cookies in greater detail.

**Links to Other Websites**

Links to other websites are presented in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed.

**Third Party Sites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to our Website, the Service and the Product. We do not exercise control over other websites that provide information, banners, advertisements or links from within the Website or the Product. 

These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personally identifiable information from you. Other websites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personally identifiable information that you submit. We encourage you to read the privacy policies and other terms of the other websites.

**Payment Service Providers**

By using Chargeable Products (as further described in our Terms) and/or when making a purchase from us, you may be required to use our Partners (e.g. Heroku, Inc., a cloud application platform) and/or trusted payment processors and/or credit agencies (e.g. BlueSnap, Inc., an e-commerce payments company) (Collectively, “ **Payment Service Providers** ”). 

Your use of such Payment Service Provider services will be governed by their own terms of use and privacy policy statement, which apply to their collection of your financial information, such as credit card information. 

To the extent permitted by law, such information resulting from a transaction by you (with the exception of certain confidential payment data), could be shared by such Payment Service Provider with us. We are not liable for any use or disclosure of information that Payment Service Providers receive from you. 

You acknowledge and agree that any credit card and/or other billing and payment information that you provide directly to us may be shared by us with the Payment Service Providers solely for the purposes of checking credit, effecting payment to us and servicing your account. 

We will treat such information as personally identifiable information. We may always retain and use such information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims and enforce our agreements.

Certain products and services include features that collect additional personally identifiable information for other purposes, as described in the applicable customer agreement. For detailed information, please refer to the applicable product or service description.

**Job applicants**

If you are making a job application or inquiry, you may provide us with a copy of your CV or other relevant information that contains your personally identifiable information. 

We will ask for your consent to use and save the information that you provide in your job application and will use this information for the purpose of considering your application or inquiry. Except when you explicitly request otherwise, we may keep this information on file for future reference.

**Market research**

If you participate in surveys, we may use your personally identifiable information to carry out market research. This research is conducted for our internal business and training purposes and will improve our understanding of our users‘ demographics, interests and behavior. 

This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis and therefore does not individually identify any user.

#### **2\. How We Use Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information is used for the following purposes: 

  * to provide the Product, 
  * to administer your use of the Product and any accounts you may have with us, 
  * to personalize your experience, 
  * to provide to you Product announcements, 
  * to provide you with further information and offers from us or third parties that we believe you may find useful or interesting, such as newsletters, marketing or promotional materials, 
  * on behalf of and according to instructions of a third party, such as our advertising partners, 
  * to enforce our Terms,
  * to comply with court orders and warrants, and assist law enforcement agencies, to collect debts, prevent fraud, misappropriation, infringements, identity thefts and any other misuse of the Service, and to take any action in any legal dispute or proceeding.
  * to resolve any disputes between users of the Site and us; and 
  * as described in Section 4: Information Sharing and Disclosure.

We use information that is **not** personally identifiable for the above purposes and to: 

  * monitor and analyze use of the Product and for the technical administration of the Site, 
  * improve the Site and the Product, 
  * generate and derive useful data and information concerning the interests, characteristics and website use behavior of our users, and 
  * verify that users of the Product meet the criteria required to process their requests. 

We use information collected on our web site in the aggregate to better understand your use of the Website and to enhance your enjoyment and experience. 

This data is used for statistical purposes as well as to help customize the user experience as you browse the web site.. For further information, see the Aggregated and Analytical Information section in this policy.

**Combined Information.**

We  combine certain personally identifiable information with non-personally identifiable information in order to allow us to create information packages and services that are better tailored to your interests and preferences. 

Among other things, linking this information may allow us generally to improve and personalize the Site and the Product. If we combine or link any information with your personally identifiable information, the resulting combination will be treated as personally identifiable information under this Policy.

**Purchase of Products and Services**

If you purchase or use our products or services, we will use your personally identifiable information and (where applicable) payment information for purposes which include but are not limited to:

  * verifying your credentials;
  * verifying your usage of the products and services in accordance with the terms and conditions of your agreement with us;
  * providing training sessions for which you have registered;
  * providing maintenance and technical support;
  * providing information about product upgrades, updates and renewals;
  * generating logs, statistics and reports on service usage and service performance;
  * developing and enhancing products and services;
  * processing orders and generating billing information.

We will use information collected from the Site in order to contact you if necessary, including, but not limited to, sending you reminders and notices about the Service, sending commercial and marketing information about our Service, and contacting you when you are using wrong paths to access the website or are breaching restrictions on the use of the website. 

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such announcements, information or offers, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communication. See also the Choice Section in this policy **.**

We may also use this information to block IP addresses where there is misuse use of the web site.

#### **3\. The Personally** **Identifiable Information That You Upload**

The content you upload to the Service, whether from your own device or from a cloud-based hosting service, including any data, text, graphic, audio-visual files, may include personally identifiable information. Based on your preferences, the uploaded content may be accessible to others.

Please use caution when uploading the content, and avoid any involuntary disclosure of your personally identifiable information or disclosure of others’ personally identifiable information without their consent.

#### **4\. Information Sharing and Disclosure**

We do not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information. We will share your personally identifiable information with service providers and other third parties, if necessary to fulfill the purposes for collecting the information. Any such third party will commit to protect your privacy as required under the applicable law and this policy.

**Service Providers**

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate the Product, to provide the Product on our behalf and to perform services related to administration of the Product or the Site (including, without limitation, bill and credit card payment processing, maintenance, hosting and database management services and administration). 

These third parties have access to your personally identifiable information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated to comply with this Policy.

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement**

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties in response to lawful requests and to comply with the law. 

We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties if we believe it necessary: 

  * to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet law enforcement or national security requirements, claims or legal processes (including but not limited to subpoenas);
  * to protect our or a third party’s property rights; 
  * to protect the safety of the public or any person; 
  * to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be posing a risk of being illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable.

**Business Transfers.**

We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including among others your personally identifiable information and Log Data, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of all or substantially all of our shares or assets, or in the event of our bankruptcy. We will also share Information with our business affiliates. 

**Aggregated and Analytical Information.**

We may share aggregated information generated as a result of your use of the Product, that includes non-personally identifiable information and Log Data, with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling, other commercial purposes and to deliver targeted advertising about other products and services. 

We use the standard analytics tools of Google Analytics and we will use additional or other analytics tools, from time to time, to learn about how you and other users use the Service, in support of our Service-related activities and operations. 

The privacy practices of these tools are subject to their own privacy policies. You can review the Google Analytics Privacy Policy at: 

[http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html).

Any aggregated information shared in these contexts is based on anonymous, statistical or aggregated information and we share it with our partners only for legitimate business purposes. 

It does not contain personally identifiable information and It has no effect on your privacy, because there is no reasonable way to extract data from the aggregated information that we or others can associate specifically to your personally identifiable information.

#### **5\. Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request in writing a list of the categories of personally identifiable information relating to third parties to which we have disclosed certain categories of personally identifiable information during the preceding year, for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. 

To make such a request, please contact us at: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com).

#### **6\. Your Choice**

At any time, you can unsubscribe our mailing lists or newsletters, by sending us an opt-out request to: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com).

At any time you can stop using the Redis Labs website. Termination of your Redis Labs Service account is subject to the terms of your subscription agreement with us. 

Note that if one of our customers uploaded content to our Service with your personally identifiable information, then you can contact our customer who uploaded that content and request to remove your personally identifiable information.

At any time, you can exercise your following opt-out options: 

  * object to the disclosure of your personally identifiable information to a third party, other than to third parties who act as our agents to perform tasks on our behalf and under our instructions; or, 
  * object to the use of your personally identifiable information for a purpose that is materially different from the purposes for which we originally collected such information, pursuant to this policy, or you subsequently authorized such use. 

You can exercise your choice by contacting us at: [privacy@redislabs.com](mailto:privacy@redislabs.com).

We request and collect minimal personally identifiable information that we need for the purposes that we describe in this policy. Following the termination or expiration of the Service, we will stop collecting any personally identifiable information from or about you. 

However, we will store and continue using or making available your personally identifiable information according with our data retention section in this policy.

Web browsers offer a “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signal. A DNT signal is a HTTP header field indicating your preference for tracking your activities on a service or through cross-site user tracking. Our Service does not respond to DNT signals.

#### **7\. Accessing Your Personally Identifiable Information**

If you find that the information on your account is not accurate, complete or up-to-date, please provide us the necessary information to correct it.

At any time, you can contact us at: legal@redislabs.com and request to access the personally identifiable information that we keep about you. 

We will ask you to provide us certain credentials to make sure that you are who you claim to be and to the extent required under the applicable law, will make good-faith efforts to locate your personally identifiable information that you request to access.. 

If you are eligible for the right of access under the applicable law, you can obtain confirmation from us of whether we are processing personally identifiable information about you, and receive a copy of that data, so that you could –  

  * verify its accuracy and the lawfulness of its processing;
  * request the correction, amendment or deletion of your personally identifiable information if it is inaccurate or if you believe that the processing of your personally identifiable information is in violation of the applicable law.

We will use judgement and due care to redact from the data which we will make available to you, personally identifiable information related to others.

#### **8\. Your EU Data Subject Rights**

If EU data protection laws apply to the processing of your personal data by Redis Labs, then the following terms apply: 

For the purposes of the Redis Labs database platform service, we are a data processor and our customers are data controllers, or data processors as well. Redis Labs’ data processing addendum, which is available at:[https://redislabs.com/terms/services-terms/](https://redislabs.com/terms/services-terms/) applies to such processing. 

Where we process your personal data as a data controller, the processing is based on the following lawful grounds: 

  * All processing of your personal data which are not based on the lawful grounds indicated below, are based on your consent. 
  * We process your account and payment details to perform the contract with you. 
  * We will process your personal data to comply with a legal obligation and to protect your and others’ vital interests. 
  * We will further rely on our legitimate interests, which we believe are not overridden by your fundamental rights and freedoms, for the following purposes: 
    * Communications with you, including direct marketing where you are our client or a user of our client, or where you make contact with us through our website and other digital assets. 
    * Cyber security
    * Support, customer relations, service operations
    * Enhancements and improvements to yours and other users’ experience with our services. 
    * Fraud detection and misuse of the Service.

Where Redis Labs processes your personal data as a data controller, then in addition to your rights under other sections in this policy, you have the following rights:

  * AT ANY TIME, CONTACT US IF YOU WANT TO WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA. EXERCISING THIS RIGHT WILL NOT AFFECT THE LAWFULNESS OF PROCESSING BASED ON CONSENT BEFORE ITS WITHDRAWAL.
  * Request to delete or restrict access to your personal data. We will review your request and use our judgment, pursuant to the provisions of the applicable law, to reach a decision about your request. 
  * If you exercise one (or more) of the above-mentioned rights, in accordance with the provisions of applicable law, you may request to be informed that third parties that hold your personal data, in accordance with this policy, will act accordingly.
  * You may ask to transfer your personal data in accordance with your right to data portability. 
  * You may object to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. Additional information about this right is available under the Choice section in this policy. 
  * You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affecting you. 
  * You have a right to lodge a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority of your habitual residence, place of work or of an alleged infringement of the GDPR. 

A summary and further details about your rights under EU data protection laws, is available on the EU Commission’s website at: [https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/reform/rights-citizens_en](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/reform/rights-citizens_en). 

Note that when you send us a request to exercise your rights, we will need to reasonably authenticate your identity and location. We will ask you to provide us credentials to make sure that you are who you claim to be and will further ask you questions to understand the nature and scope of your request. 

If we need to delete your personal data following your request, it will take some time until we completely delete residual copies of your personal data from our active servers and from our backup systems. 

If you have any concerns about the way we process your personal data, you are welcome to contact our privacy team at: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com). We will look into your inquiry and make good-faith efforts to respond promptly. 

#### **9\. Data Retention**

We retain different types of information for different periods, depending on the purposes for processing the information, our legitimate business purposes as well as pursuant to legal requirements under the applicable law.

We retain personally identifiable information as part of our Service data, to provide our customers with the Service and as needed to perform our business activities. 

We maintain contact details, to help us stay in contact with you. 

We may need to keep the information about the payment transactions that you made for several years due to tax related requirements, for accounts settling, record keeping, archiving and legal issues.

We may keep aggregated non-identifiable information without limitation, and to the extent reasonable we will delete or de-identify potentially identifiable information, when we no longer need to process the information.

In any case, as long as you use the Service, we will keep information about you, unless we are required by law to delete it, or if we decide to remove it at our discretion.

#### **10\. Information Security**

We are concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ a variety of measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access and disclosure. We implement systems, applications and procedures to secure your personally identifiable information, to minimize the risks of theft, damage, loss of information, or unauthorized access or use of information. 

We take reasonable steps to maintain the security of the personally identifiable information that we collect, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers, as well as installing electronic security systems that guard against unauthorized access. 

However, no one can guarantee a completely secured data transmission over the Internet. Accordingly, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, so you do so at your own risk. 

If you have been given log-in details to provide you with access to certain parts of our web site (for example our Partner Portal), you are responsible for keeping those details confidential.  

  * Personally identifiable informationIf you receive an e-mail asking you to update your Personally identifiable information, do not reply and please contact us at legal@redislabs.com.

#### **11\. International Processing or Transfer**

Part of our Service is a web-based service. We store and process information within the European Union and in the United States on our cloud-based services’ sites. 

From time to time, we will make operational decisions which will have an impact on the sites in which we maintain personally identifiable information. We make sure that our data hosting service providers, provide us with adequate confidentiality and security commitments. 

If you are a resident in a jurisdiction where transfer of your personally identifiable information to another jurisdiction requires your consent, then you provide us your express and unambiguous consent to such transfer. You can contact our privacy team at: legal@redislabs.com for further information about data transfer.

#### **12\. Our Policy Toward Children**

If you are under the age of 16, you do not have permission to use the Website and the Product. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. 

If you are between the ages of 16 and 18, please let your parent or guardian know about this Policy and get his or her permission before you give us any of your personal identifiable information. 

If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personally identifiable information without their consent, he or she should contact us at legal@redislabs.com. If we become aware that a minor has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information from our files.

#### **13\. Dispute Resolution**

We do periodical assessments of our data processing and privacy practices, to make sure that we comply with this policy, to update the policy when we believe that we need to, and to verify that we display the policy properly and in an accessible manner. 

If you have any concerns about the way we process your personally identifiable information, you are welcome to contact our privacy team at: legal@redislabs.com, or write to us. Our address is published on our website at: www.redislabs.com and, if applicable, is indicated in your subscription agreement with us.

We will look into your query and make good-faith efforts to resolve any existing or potential dispute with you.

#### **14\. Changes to the Privacy Policy**

We will update this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will post a notice of these changes on the Site and in this Policy. 

If the updates have minor if any consequences, they will take effect 7 days after we post a notice on the Site. Substantial changes will be effective 30 days after we initially posted the notice. 

Until the new policy takes effect, if it materially reduces the protection of your privacy rights under the previously existing policy, you can choose not to accept it and terminate your use of the Service. 

Continuing to use the Service after the new policy takes effect means that you agree to the new policy. Note that if we need to adapt the policy to legal requirements, the new policy will become effective immediately or as required by law.If you would like us to notify you by email when we update this Policy, please send an email to legal@redislabs.com. 

#### **15\. Incorporation to the Terms of Use**

This policy is an integral part of our [Terms of Use](https://cloudinary.com/tos) or, if applicable, of any other Service subscription agreement entered into between you (or the entity that you are acting on its behalf) and us.   

#### **16\. Contact Us**

Please contact our Privacy Compliance Team at: [legal@redislabs.com](mailto:legal@redislabs.com) for further information.

#### **ADDENDUM A: The Cookies Policy**

Redis Labs (“us”, “we”, or “our”) uses cookies on the https://redislabs.com website (the “website”). By using the website, you consent to the use of cookies.

Our Cookies Policy explains what cookies are, how we use cookies, how third-parties we may partner with may use cookies on the website, your choices regarding cookies and further information about cookies.

#### **What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small pieces of text sent to your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Service or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Service more useful to you.

Cookies can be “persistent” or “session” cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your personal computer or mobile device when you go offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

#### **How Redis Labs Uses Cookies?**

When you use and access the website, we may place a number of cookies files in your web browser.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * To enable certain functions of the website;
  * To provide analytics;
  * To store your preferences;
  * To enable advertisements delivery, including behavioral advertising;
  * We use both session and persistent cookies on the Service and we use different types of cookies to run the Service.

**Essential** **cookies**. We may use cookies to remember information that changes the way the website behaves or looks, such as a user’s language preference on the website.

**Accounts-related** **cookies**. We may use accounts-related cookies to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use of user accounts. We may use these cookies to remember information that changes the way the website behaves or looks, such as the “remember me” functionality.

**Analytics** **cookies**. We may use analytics cookies to track information how the website is used so that we can make improvements. We may also use analytics cookies to test new advertisements, pages, features or new functionality of the website to see how our users react to them.

**Advertising** **cookies**. These type of cookies are used to deliver advertisements on and through the website and track the performance of these advertisements. These cookies may also be used to enable third-party advertising networks to deliver ads that may be relevant to you based upon your activities or interests.

#### **Third-Party Cookies**

In addition to our own cookies, we may also use various third-parties cookies to report usage statistics of the website, deliver advertisements on and through the Service, and so on.

#### **What Are Your Choices Regarding Cookies?**

If you’d like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help pages of your web browser.

Please note, however, that if you delete cookies or refuse to accept them, you might not be able to use all of the features we offer, you may not be able to store your preferences, and some of our pages might not display properly.

For the Chrome web browser, please visit this page from Google:[ https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/32050)

For the Internet Explorer web browser, please visit this page from Microsoft:

For the Firefox web browser, please visit this page from Mozilla:

[https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored)

For the Safari web browser, please visit this page from Apple:

For any other web browser, please visit your web browser’s official web pages.

#### **Where Can You Find More Information About Cookies?**

You can learn more about cookies and the following third-party websites:

AllAboutCookies:[ http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

Network Advertising Initiative:[ http://www.networkadvertising.org/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)
